leagle.com 2018-06-29

# Privacy Policy | Leagle.com | A leading provider of copies of primary caselaw decisions from all Federal courts and all State higher courts

**Version Date** : June 1, 2009 

### GENERAL

This Privacy Policy explains both how we gather such information and how we may use such information, as well as how you may limit, in certain instances, our use of such information. So please read this Privacy Policy carefully.

Leagle, Inc. ("Company") respects the privacy of its users whether they use our website located at www.leagle.com ("Website") to access information resources, participate in interactive programs or simply view the Website. The following Company privacy policy ("Privacy Policy") is designed to inform you, as a user of the Website, about the types of information that Company may gather about or collect from you in connection with your use of the Website. It also is intended to explain the conditions under which Company uses and discloses that information, and your rights in relation to that information. Changes to this Privacy Policy are discussed at the end of this document. Each time you use the Website, however, the current version of this Privacy Policy will apply. Accordingly, each time you use the Website you should check the date of this Privacy Policy (which appears at the beginning of this document) and review any changes since the last time you used the Website. The Website is hosted on servers located in the United States. By using the Website, you are consenting to have your personal data transferred to and processed in the United States.

By using or accessing the Website, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy.

### CHILDREN

The Website is not intended for children under 13 years of age. Company does not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13.

### GATHERING, USE AND DISCLOSURE OF NON-PERSONALLY-IDENTIFYING INFORMATION

###  _Users of the Website Generally_

"Non-Personally-Identifying Information" is information that, without the aid of additional information, cannot be directly associated with a specific person. "Personally-Identifying Information," by contrast, is information such as a name or email address that, without more, can be directly associated with a specific person. Like most website operators, Company gathers from users of the Website Non-Personally-Identifying Information of the sort that Web browsers, depending on their settings, may make available. That information includes the user's Internet Protocol (IP) address, operating system and browser type, and the locations of the Web pages the user views right before arriving at, while navigating and immediately after leaving the Website. Company analyzes Non-Personally-Identifying Information gathered from users of the Website to help Company better understand how the Website is being used. By identifying patterns and trends in usage, Company is able to better design the Website to improve users' experiences, both in terms of content and ease of use. From time to time, Company may also release the Non-Personally-Identifying Information gathered from Website users in the aggregate, such as by publishing a report on trends in the usage of the Website.

###  _Web Cookies_

A "Web Cookie" is a string of information that a website stores on a user's computer, and that the user's browser provides to the website each time the user submits a query to the site. Company uses Web Cookies to track the pages that users visit during each Website session, both to help Company improve users' experiences and to help Company understand how the Website is being used. As with other Non-Personally-Identifying Information gathered from users of the Website, Company analyzes and discloses in aggregated form information gathered using Web Cookies, so as to help Company, its partners and others better understand how the Website is being used. Company does not attempt to link information gathered using Web Cookies to Personally-Identifying Information. COMPANY USERS WHO DO NOT WISH TO HAVE WEB COOKIES PLACED ON THEIR COMPUTERS SHOULD SET THEIR BROWSERS TO REFUSE WEB COOKIES BEFORE ACCESSING THE WEBSITE, WITH THE UNDERSTANDING THAT CERTAIN FEATURES OF THE WEBSITE MAY NOT FUNCTION PROPERLY WITHOUT THE AID OF WEB COOKIES. WEBSITE USERS WHO REFUSE WEB COOKIES ASSUME ALL RESPONSIBILITY FOR ANY RESULTING LOSS OF FUNCTIONALITY. 

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit the Website. These companies may use information (not including any Personally-Identifying Information) about your visits to this and other websites that are contained in Web Cookies in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. Using a tool created by the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://networkadvertising.org/), you can [opt out](http://networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp) of several third party ad servers' and networks' Web Cookies simultaneously. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please follow the following link: <http://networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>. Please contact us if you would like to know the identity of the third-party advertising companies we are currently using to serve ads.

###  _Web Beacons_

A "Web Beacon" is an object that is embedded in a web page that is usually invisible to the user and allows website operators to check whether a user has viewed a particular web page. Company may use Web Beacons on the Website to count users who have visited particular pages and to deliver co-branded services. Web Beacons are not used to access users' Personally-Identifying Information; they are a technique Company may use to compile aggregated statistics about Website usage. Web Beacons collect only a limited set of information including a cookie number, time and date of a page view, and a description of the page on which the Web Beacon resides. You may not decline Web Beacons, however, they can be rendered ineffective by declining all cookies or modifying your browser setting to notify you each time a cookie is tendered and permit you to accept or decline cookies on an individual basis. Third parties are not permitted to use Web Beacons on the Website. 

### COLLECTION, USE AND DISCLOSURE OF PERSONALLY-IDENTIFYING INFORMATION 

###  _Website Registration_

As defined above, Personally-Identifying Information is information that can be directly associated with a specific person. Company collects a range of Personally-Identifying Information from and about Website users. Much of the Personally-Identifying Information collected by Company about users is information provided by users themselves at the time they register and open an account. Registration may not be required for access to resources initially. However, Company may at any time require registration for certain levels of access, in which case all provisions of this Privacy Policy relating to registration and opening an account will apply. That information may include each user's name, physical address, email address, telephone number, date of birth and other information as determined appropriate by Company from time-to-time. Company uses an external service for financial transactions with users and does not collect nor record nor retain in any fashion personal financial information including PayPal account or credit card numbers, nor does Company have access to said information. Users of the Website are under no obligation to provide Company with Personally-Identifying Information of any kind, with the caveat that a user's refusal to do so may prevent the user from using certain Website features. 

BY REGISTERING WITH OR USING THE WEBSITE, YOU CONSENT TO THE USE AND DISCLOSURE OF YOUR PERSONALLY IDENTIFYING INFORMATION AS DESCRIBED IN THIS "COLLECTION, USE AND DISCLOSURE OF PERSONALLY-IDENTIFYING INFORMATION" SECTION.

###  _Online Forums and Blogs_

Certain Personally-Identifying Information collected from users is disclosed as a matter of course as a result of those users' use of the Website and participation in online forums, commenting on blog posts, and otherwise. USERS ASSUME ALL RESPONSIBILITY FOR ANY LOSS OF PRIVACY OR OTHER HARM RESULTING FROM THEIR VOLUNTARY DISCLOSURE OF PERSONALLY IDENTIFYING INFORMATION.

###  _Company Communications_

We may occasionally use your name and email address to send you notifications regarding new services offered by the Website that we think you may find valuable. We may also send you service-related announcements from time to time through the general operation of the service. Generally, you may opt out of such emails, though we reserve the right to send you notices about your account even if you opt out of all voluntary email notifications.

###  _DMCA Infringement Notifications, Notices of Violations of Website Terms of Use and Other Communications Directed to Company_

By submitting a copyright infringement notification under the Digital Millennium Copyright Act (DMCA) (explained further in our Terms of Use) or other communication (including communications about content stored on or transmitted through the Website) you consent to have such communication forwarded to the person or entity who stored, transmitted or linked to the content addressed by your communication, in order to facilitate a prompt resolution. For notices of violations of our Terms of Use or other communications (but not DMCA copyright infringement notifications), upon request Company will edit out your name and contact information. However, DMCA copyright infringement notifications (including any personally identifiable information set forth in the notifications) will be forwarded as submitted to Company without any deletions.

###  _Company Disclosures_

Company will disclose Personally-Identifying Information under the following circumstances: 

  * **By Law or to Protect Rights**. Company discloses Personally-Identifying Information when required to do so by law, or in response to a subpoena or court order, or when Company believes in its sole discretion that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of Company, third parties or the public at large.

  * **Marketing Communications**. Unless users opt-out from receiving Company marketing materials upon registration, Company may email users about products and services that Company believes may be of interest to them. Company also may provide users' email information to third parties, so that those third parties may directly contact users about additional products and services. If a user wishes to opt-out of having their email information provided to third parties at any time after registration, they may do so by contacting us at [info@leagle.com](mailto:info@leagle.com). Even after opting-out, a user may continue to receive marketing emails from third parties to whom Company already has provided the user's email information. Users will be responsible for directly contacting such third parties to request cessation of further marketing emails.

  * **Third Party Service Providers**. We cooperate with other companies to provide our services to you, and therefore we allow them access to the necessary Personally-Identifying Information. This cooperation involves, but is not limited to, hosting of the Website, technical maintenance, database and communication support, and legal expertise. 

  * **Business Transfers; Bankruptcy**. Company reserves the right to transfer all Personally-Identifying Information in its possession to a successor organization in the event of a merger, acquisition, or bankruptcy or other sale of all or a portion of Company's assets. Other than to the extent ordered by a bankruptcy or other court, the use and disclosure of all transferred Personally-Identifying Information will be subject to this Privacy Policy, or to a new privacy policy if you are given notice of that new privacy policy and are given an opportunity to affirmatively opt-out of it. Personally-Identifying Information submitted or collected after a transfer, however, may be subject to a new privacy policy adopted by the successor organization. 

###  _Changing Personally-Identifying Information; Account Termination_

You may at any time change your Personally-Identifying Information by logging into your account, following the "My Account" link and then going to "Edit Profile". Upon your request, we will deactivate or delete your account and contact information from our active databases. Such information will be deactivated or deleted as soon as practicable based on your account activity and accordance with our deactivation policy and applicable law. To make this request, e-mail us at [info@leagle.com](mailto:info@leagle.com). We will retain in our files some personal information to prevent fraud, to troubleshoot problems, to assist with any investigations, to enforce our Terms of Use and to comply with legal requirements as is permitted by law. Therefore, you should not expect that all your personal information will be completely removed from our databases in response to your requests. Additionally, we keep a history of changed information to investigate suspected fraud with your account.

###  _General Use_

We use the Personally-Identifiable Information in the file we maintain about you, and other information we obtain from your current and past activities on the Website to: resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, measure consumer interest in our services, reward you for the ads you watch, inform you of offers, products, services, and updates, customize your experience, detect and protect us against error, fraud and other criminal activity, enforce our Terms of Use, and as otherwise described to you at the time of collection. At times, we may look across multiple users to identify problems. In particular, we may examine your Personally-Identifiable Information to identify users using multiple user IDs or aliases. We may compare and review your Personally-Identifiable Information for accuracy and to detect errors and omissions.

### CONTESTS, GIVEAWAYS AND SURVEYS. 

From time to time, Company may offer Website users the opportunity to participate in contests, giveaways and other promotions. Any information submitted in connection with such activities will be treated in accordance with this Privacy Policy. From time to time, Company may also ask Website users to participate in surveys designed to help Company improve the Website. Any Personally-Identifying Information provided to Company in connection with any survey will be used only in relation to that survey, and will be disclosed to third parties not bound by this Privacy Policy only in non-personally-identifying, aggregated form.

###  _EMAIL TO FRIENDS FEATURE AND REFERRAL PROGRAM_

Company offers users the ability to send friends emails about the Website. If users choose to use this feature, be assured that Company only uses friends' email addresses on a one-time basis to send the requested email.

### COLLECTION AND USE OF INFORMATION BY THIRD PARTIES GENERALLY

Company contractually prohibits its contractors, affiliates, vendors and suppliers from disclosing Personally-Identifying Information received from Company, other than in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Third parties are under no obligation to comply with this Privacy Policy, however, with respect to Personally-Identifying Information that users provide directly to those third parties or that those third parties collect for themselves. Company neither owns nor controls the third-party websites accessible through the Website. Thus, this Privacy Policy does not apply to information provided to or gathered by the third parties that operate them. Before visiting a third-party, whether by means of a link on the Website or otherwise, and before providing any Personally-Identifying Information to any third party, users should inform themselves of the privacy policies and practices (if any) of the third party responsible for that website, and should take those steps necessary to, in those users' discretion, protect their privacy.

### SECURITY

We take security of your Personally-Identifying Information seriously and use reasonable electronic, personnel, and physical measures to protect it from loss, theft, alteration, or misuse. However, please be advised that even the best security measures cannot fully eliminate all risks.

### PRIVACY POLICY CHANGES

Company may, in its sole discretion, change this Privacy Policy from time to time. Any and all changes to Company's Privacy Policy will be reflected on this page and the date new versions are posted will be stated at the top of this Privacy Policy. Unless Company obtains your express consent, any revised Privacy Policy will apply only to information collected after such time as the revised Privacy Policy takes effect, and not to information collected under any earlier Privacy Policies. Users should regularly check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Company will always post new versions of the Privacy Policy on the Website. However, Company may, as determined in its discretion, decide to notify users of changes made to this Privacy Policy via email or otherwise. Accordingly, it is important that users always maintain and update their contact information.

### CONTACT

If you have any questions regarding our Privacy Policy, please contact our privacy officer at:

Leagle Inc. Privacy Officer

Leagle, Inc. 

Fax: (310) 388-0502

Email: [info@leagle.com](mailto:info@leagle.com)
